Miller, N mss. II, 1928-1991 LMC 2609
Lilly Library
Miller, N mss. II
1928-1991
2007
Lilly Library
Miller, Nolan, 1907-2006
LMC 2609
17 Boxes 17 standard
The Miller, N mss. II consists of the manuscripts, teaching materials, correspondence, journals, and other materials of writer Nolan Miller.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Nolan Miller (1907-2006) was a author, editor of The Antioch Review, and professor of English at Antioch College in Ohio. He has published four novels and various short stories over several decades.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: I. Novels, II. Unpublished Novels, III. Miscellaneous Novel Drafts, IV. Short Stories, V. Other Writings, VI. Journals, VII. Correspondence, VIII. Teaching Materials, IX. Miscellaneous
Scope and Content Note
I. Novels contains manuscripts of Miller's published novels The Merry Innocents, A Moth of Time, and Why Am I So Beat?. II. Unpublished Novels contains the manuscripts for Miller's unpublished novels and novellas. III. Miscellaneous Novel Drafts includes various drafts, exerpts, and parts of novels. IV. Short Stories contain manuscripts of Miller's extensive short stories. V. Other Writings includes Miller's drafts of his autobiography, the Living Language textbook, poetry, short plays, and other pieces of fiction and nonfiction writings. VI. Journals includes the journals of Miller from 1942 to 1963. VII. Correspondence consists of letters to and from Miller from 1944-1991. VIII. Teaching Materials includes various workshops, lectures, evaluations, and other materials related to Miller's time at Antioch College. IX. Miscellaneous includes all other items, including photos, clippings, notes, notebooks, and periodicals containing Miller's publications.
Related Material
See Miller, N mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 2007
Miller, Nolan, 1907-2006
- I. NOVELS
  - The Merry Innocents
    - Draft with corrections Part 1 (Box 1)
    - Draft with corrections Part 2 (Box 1)
    - Draft with corrections Part 3 (Box 1)
    - Draft with corrections Part 4 (Box 1)
  - A Moth of Time
    - Ver 1 - Draft with corrections Ch. 1-5 (Box 1)
    - Ver 1 - Draft with corrections Ch. 6-10 (Box 1)
    - Ver 1 - Draft with corrections Ch. 11-15 (Box 1)
    - Ver 1 - Draft with corrections Ch. 16-20 (Box 1)
    - Ver 1 - Draft with corrections Ch. 26-30 (Box 1)
    - Ver 1 - Draft with corrections Ch. 31-35 (Box 1)
    - Ver 1 - Draft with corrections Ch. 36-40 (Box 1)
    - Ver 1 - Draft with corrections Ch. 41-45 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 1 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 2 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 3 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 4 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 5 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 6 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 7 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 8 (Box 1)
    - Ver 2 - Draft with corrections Part 9 (Box 1)
    - Ver 3 - Draft with corrections Part 1 (Box 1)
    - Ver 3 - Draft with corrections Part 2 (Box 1)
    - Ver 3 - Draft with corrections Part 3 (Box 1)
    - Ver 3 - Draft with corrections Part 4 (Box 1)
    - Ver 3 - Draft with corrections Part 5 (Box 1)
    - Ver 3 - Draft with corrections Part 6 (Box 1)
    - Ver 3 - Draft with corrections Part 7 (Box 1)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 1 (Box 1)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 2 (Box 1)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 3 (Box 1)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 4 (Box 1)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 5 (Box 1)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 6 (Box 2)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 7 (Box 2)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 8 (Box 2)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 9 (Box 2)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 10 (Box 2)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 11 (Box 2)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 12 (Box 2)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 13 (Box 2)
    - Ver 4 - Draft with corrections Part 14 (Box 2)
    - Book mock set up (Box 2)
  - Why Am I So Beat?
    - Synopsis (Box 2)
    - Various draft fragments Part 1 (Box 2)
    - Various draft fragments Part 2 (Box 2)
    - Various draft fragments Part 3 (Box 2)
    - Galley (Box 2)
    - Uncorrected galley (Box 2)
- II. UNPUBLISHED NOVELS
  - The Boy from Detroit
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 1-5 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 6-10 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 11-13 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 14-16 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 17-20 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 21-23 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 24-26 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 27-30 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 31-35 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 36-41 (Box 2)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 42-43 (Box 2)
    - Misc (Box 2)
  - Intelligent Fountains
    - Part 1 (Box 2)
    - Part 2 (Box 2)
    - Part 3 (Box 2)
    - Part 4 (Box 2)
  - Full Recovery
    - Ch. 1-5 (Box 2)
    - Ch. 6-10 (Box 2)
    - Ch. 11-15 (Box 2)
    - Ch. 16-20 (Box 2)
    - Misc drafts Part 1 (Box 2)
    - Misc drafts Part 2 (Box 2)
    - Misc drafts Part 3 (Box 2)
    - Misc drafts Part 4 (Box 2)
  - The Good Provider
    - Part 1 (Box 3)
    - Part 2 (Box 3)
    - Part 3 (Box 3)
    - Part 4 (Box 3)
  - It's All Done with Mirrors
    - Book 1 (Box 3)
    - Book 2 Part 1 (Box 3)
    - Book 2 Part 2 (Box 3)
    - Book 3 (Box 3)
  - The Lamb and the Bell
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 1-5 (Box 3)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 6-10 (Box 3)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 11-15 (Box 3)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 16-20 (Box 3)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 21-25 (Box 3)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 26-30 (Box 3)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 31-35 (Box 3)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 36-42 (Box 3)
  - Land Above Water
    - Ch. 1-5 (Box 3)
    - Ch. 6-10 (Box 3)
    - Ch. 11-15 (Box 3)
    - Ch. 16-21 (Box 3)
  - A Light on the Path
    - Part 1 (Box 3)
    - Part 2 (Box 3)
    - Part 3 (Box 3)
  - Love and Evil
    - Part 1 (Box 3)
    - Part 2 (Box 3)
    - Part 3 (Box 3)
  - The Lower Straits
    - Typescript Part 1 (Box 3)
    - Typescript Part 2 (Box 3)
    - Typescript Part 3 (Box 3)
    - Typescript Part 4 (Box 3)
    - Typescript Part 5 (Box 3)
    - Typescript 2 Part 1 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 2 Part 2 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 2 Part 3 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 2 Part 4 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 3 Part 1 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 3 Part 2 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 3 Part 3 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 3 Part 4 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 3 Part 5 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 4 Part 1 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 4 Part 2 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 4 Part 3 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 4 Part 4 (Box 4)
    - Typescript 4 Part 5 (Box 4)
  - Me!
    - Part 1 (Box 4)
    - Part 2 (Box 4)
    - Part 3 (Box 4)
    - Part 4 (Box 4)
    - Part 5 (Box 4)
    - Part 6 (Box 4)
    - Part 7 (Box 4)
    - Part 8 (Box 4)
    - Part 9 (Box 4)
    - Part 10 (Box 4)
    - Part 11 (Box 4)
    - Misc drafts (Box 4)
  - The Middle-Aged Menagerie
    - Part 1 (Box 4)
    - Part 2 (Box 4)
    - Part 3 (Box 4)
    - Part 4 (Box 4)
    - Ver 2 Part 1 (Box 4)
    - Ver 2 Part 2 (Box 4)
    - Ver 2 Part 3 (Box 4)
    - Ver 2 Part 4 (Box 4)
    - Ver 3 Part 1 (Box 4)
    - Ver 3 Part 2 (Box 4)
    - Ver 3 Part 3 (Box 4)
    - Ver 3 Part 4 (Box 4)
    - Ver 3 Part 5 (Box 4)
    - Ver 3 Part 6 (Box 4)
  - Missing Persons
    - Part 1 (Box 4)
    - Part 2 (Box 4)
    - Part 3 (Box 4)
  - The Naked Daughters of Oak Hill
    - Book 1 Ch. 1-2 Proof (Box 4)
    - Original - Book 1 Ch. 1 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 1 Ch. 2-3 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 2 Ch. 1 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 2 Ch. 2 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 2 Ch. 3-4 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 3 Ch. 1-5 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 3 Ch. 6-9 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 4 Ch. 1-5 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 4 Ch. 6-10 (Box 5)
    - Original - Book 4 Ch. 11-16 (Box 5)
    - Part 1 p. 1-50 (Box 5)
    - Part 2 p. 51-100 (Box 5)
    - Part 3 p. 101-150 (Box 5)
    - Part 4 p. 151-200 (Box 5)
    - Part 5 p. 201-250 (Box 5)
    - Part 6 p. 251-300 (Box 5)
    - Part 7 p. 301-350 (Box 5)
    - Part 8 p. 351-400 (Box 5)
    - Part 9 p. 401-450 (Box 5)
    - Part 10 p. 450-509 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 1 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 2 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 3 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 4 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 5 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 6 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 7 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 8 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 9 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 10 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 11 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 12 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 13 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 14 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 15 (Box 5)
    - Various drafts Part 16 (Box 5)
  - The Names of Things
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 1 - Book 1 Ch. 1 (Box 5)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 1 - Book 1 Ch. 2 (Box 5)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 1 - Book 1 Ch. 3 (Box 5)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 1 - Book 2 Ch. 1-2 (Box 5)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 1 - Book 2 Ch. 3 (Box 5)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 1 - Book 2 Ch. 4 (Box 5)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 1 - Book 3 Ch. 1 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 1 - Book 3 Ch. 2-3 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 2 - Book 1 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 2 - Book 2 Ch. 1-2 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 2 - Book 2 Ch. 3-4 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 2 - Book 3 Ch. 1 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ver. 2 - Book 3 Ch. 2-3 (Box 6)
  - The Nature of Sam
    - Part 1.1 (Box 6)
    - Part 1.2 (Box 6)
    - Part 2.1 (Box 6)
    - Part 2.2 (Box 6)
  - No Terror Like the End
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 1-5 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 6-10 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 11-15 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Ch. 16-20 (Box 6)
  - Not Done with Mirrors
    - Draft with corrections Part 1 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Part 2 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Part 3 (Box 6)
  - The Obsession
    - Part 1 (Box 6)
    - Part 2 (Box 6)
    - Part 3 (Box 6)
    - Part 4 (Box 6)
    - Part 5 (Box 6)
    - Part 6 (Box 6)
    - Part 7 (Box 6)
    - Part 8 (Box 6)
  - The Orchard
    - Draft with corrections Part 1 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Part 2 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Part 3 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Part 4 (Box 6)
    - Draft with corrections Part 5 (Box 6)
  - The Primitives
    - Part 1 (Box 6)
    - Part 2 (Box 6)
    - Part 3 (Box 6)
    - Part 4 (Box 6)
  - Sons and Daughters
    - Ver 1 - Part 1.1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 1.2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 2.1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 2.2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 3 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 4 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 5.1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 5.2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 6 (Box 7)
    - Ver 1 - Part 7 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 1.1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 1.2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 2.1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 2.2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 3 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 4 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 5 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 6 (Box 7)
    - Ver 2 - Part 7 (Box 7)
    - Ver 3 - Book 1, Part 1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 3 - Book 1, Part 2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 3 - Book 2, Part 1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 3 - Book 2, Part 2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 3 - Book 2, Part 3 (Box 7)
    - Ver 3 - Book 2, Part 4 (Box 7)
    - Ver 4 - Part 1.1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 4 - Part 1.2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 4 - Part 2.1 (Box 7)
    - Ver 4 - Part 2.2 (Box 7)
    - Ver 4 - Part 3 (Box 7)
    - Ver 4 - Part 4 (Box 7)
    - Ver 4 - Part 5 (Box 8)
    - Ver 4 - Part 6 (Box 8)
    - Ver 4 - Part 7 (Box 8)
    - Ver 5 - Part 1 (Box 8)
    - Ver 5 - Part 2 (Box 8)
    - Ver 5 - Part 3 (Box 8)
    - Ver 6 - Part 1 (Box 8)
    - Ver 6 - Part 2 (Box 8)
    - Ver 6 - Part 3 (Box 8)
    - Ver 7 - Part 1 (Box 8)
    - Ver 7 - Part 2 (Box 8)
    - Ver 7 - Part 3 (Box 8)
    - Ver 7 - Part 4 (Box 8)
    - Ver 7 - Part 5 (Box 8)
    - Ver 8 - Part 1 (Box 8)
    - Ver 8 - Part 2 (Box 8)
    - Ver 8 - Part 3 (Box 8)
    - Ver 8 - Part 4 (Box 8)
    - Ver 8 - Part 5 (Box 8)
    - Ver 8 - Part 6 (Box 8)
    - Ver 8 - Part 7 (Box 8)
    - Ver 8 - Part 8 (Box 8)
  - The Straphanger's Serenade
    - Ch. 1 (Box 8)
    - Ch. 2 (Box 8)
    - Ch. 3 (Box 8)
  - Three Marriages
    - Typescript Ch. 1-5 (Box 8)
    - Typescript Ch. 6-10 (Box 8)
    - Typescript Ch. 11-13 (Box 8)
    - Typescript Ch. 14-15 (Box 8)
    - Typescript Ch. 16-17 (Box 8)
    - Typescript Ch. 18-20 (Box 8)
    - Draft with corrections Part 1 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 2 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 3 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 4 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 5 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 6 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 7 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 8 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 9 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 10 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 11 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 12 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 13 (Box 9)
    - Draft with corrections Part 14 (Box 9)
  - The Vigil
    - Part 1 (Box 9)
    - Part 2 (Box 9)
    - Part 3 (Box 9)
    - Part 4 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Part 1 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Part 2 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Part 3 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Part 4 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Part 5 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Part 6 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 2 Part 1 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 2 Part 2 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 2 Part 3 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 2 Part 4 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 2 Part 5 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 2 Part 6 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 2 Part 7 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 2 Part 8 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 3 Part 1 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 3 Part 2 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 3 Part 3 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 3 Part 4 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 4 Part 1 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 4 Part 2 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 5 Part 1 (Box 9)
  - Unknown Ver. 5 Part 2 (Box 9)
- III. MISCELLANEOUS NOVEL DRAFTS
  - Part 1 (Box 10)
  - Part 2 (Box 10)
  - Part 3 (Box 10)
  - Part 4 (Box 10)
  - Part 5 (Box 10)
  - Part 6 (Box 10)
  - Part 7 (Box 10)
  - Part 8 (Box 10)
  - Part 9 (Box 10)
  - Part 10 (Box 10)
  - Part 11 (Box 10)
  - Part 12 (Box 10)
  - Part 13 (Box 10)
  - Part 14 (Box 10)
  - Part 15 (Box 10)
  - Part 16 (Box 10)
  - Part 17 (Box 10)
  - Part 18 (Box 10)
  - Part 19 (Box 10)
  - Part 20 (Box 10)
  - Part 21 (Box 10)
  - Part 22 (Box 10)
  - Part 23 (Box 10)
  - Part 24 (Box 10)
- IV. SHORT STORIES
  - "The Accident" (Box 10)
  - "The Adoration of Virgins" (Box 10)
  - "Again All These Questions and Again These Answers" (Box 10)
  - "Again These Questions Again" (Box 10)
  - "Alias Mr. Twistedtoes" (Box 10)
  - "All the Best Abroad" (Box 10)
  - 'Always a Matter of Words" (Box 10)
  - "Always to My Surprise" (Box 10)
  - "As High as My Heart" (Box 10)
  - "At the Bus Station" (Box 10)
  - "Attendants of Roses" (Box 10)
  - "Attendants of Roses - draft with corrections" (Box 10)
  - 'The Awakening Heart" (Box 10)
  - "Bachelor's Quarters" (Box 10)
  - 'The Blue Dress" (Box 10)
  - "A Boy Can Run" (Box 10)
  - "Breakin' John" (Box 10)
  - "Calculated Risk" (Box 11)
  - "A Child in the House" (Box 11)
  - "A Child in the House" Ver. 2 (Box 11)
  - "A Child Like Crazy" (Box 11)
  - "The Children in the House Hate Blue" (Box 11)
  - "The Chocolate Heart" (Box 11)
  - "Chocolate-Coated Straws" (Box 11)
  - "The Climate of Understanding" (Box 11)
  - "Courage, Mr. Cunningham" (Box 11)
  - "Dear Wife" (Box 11)
  - "Death and the Moth" (Box 11)
  - "Doc Aldenbrand and the Opposite Sex" (Box 11)
  - "Double Feature" (Box 11)
  - "Endless Repetitions" (Box 11)
  - "End Without Ending" (Box 11)
  - "The Engagement" (Box 11)
  - "Eye" (Box 11)
  - "A Family Affair" (Box 11)
  - "Found Money" (Box 11)
  - "A Fearful Symmetry" (Box 11)
  - "The Friendly Circle" (Box 11)
  - "The Friendly Circle" Ver. 2 (Box 11)
  - "From the Head of Zeus" (Box 11)
  - "From the Light and the Heat" (Box 11)
  - "The Gift" (Box 11)
  - "A Girl, a Ghost, and Friday Night" (Box 11)
  - 'The Girl with the One-Way Ticket" (Box 11)
  - "The Girl Who Wanted to Wait" (Box 11)
  - "Going Away and Coming Back" (Box 11)
  - "The Golden Horn" (Box 11)
  - "Gone" (Box 11)
  - "The Green Oath" (Box 11)
  - "Grief" (Box 11)
  - "Grief" Ver. 2 (Box 11)
  - "Grief" Ver. 3 (Box 11)
  - "Grief" Ver. 4 (Box 11)
  - "Hermione's Hundred Years" (Box 11)
  - "Hermione's Hundred Years" - draft with corrections (Box 11)
  - "A Home Girl Abroad" (Box 11)
  - 'Honeymoon" (Box 11)
  - "A Honeymoon Ends" (Box 11)
  - "The Heartbreakers" Ver. 1 (Box 11)
  - "The Heartbreakers" Ver. 2 (Box 11)
  - "The Heartbreakers" Ver. 3 (Box 11)
  - "The Heartbreakers" Ver. 4 (Box 11)
  - "The Heartbreakers" Ver. 5 (Box 11)
  - "The Heartbreakers" Ver. 6 (Box 11)
  - "The Imaginary Mothers" (Box 11)
  - "I'm From Joe" (Box 11)
  - "In the Camera's Eyes" (Box 11)
  - "Journey Across a River" (Box 11)
  - "Lemon Squash" (Box 11)
  - "The Lesson in Silence" (Box 11)
  - "The Less Said the Better" (Box 11)
  - "A Lesson in English" (Box 11)
  - "The Life of a Writer" (Box 11)
  - "The Life of a Writer" - draft with corrections (Box 11)
  - "Like a Story with Real People in It" (Box 11)
  - "Like You Have to Listen to Music" (Box 11)
  - "Little Deeds of Kindness" (Box 11)
  - "Look at the Moon, Look at the Night" (Box 11)
  - "Love 2000" (Box 11)
  - "Love 2000" - draft with corrections (Box 11)
  - "Love 2000" - handwritten draf (Box 11)
  - "Love and Evil" (Box 11)
  - "The Love Letter" (Box 11)
  - "Love and Mr. Sasser" (Box 11)
  - "Loveliest of Trees" (Box 11)
  - "The Luckiest Girl in the World" (Box 11)
  - "MacBeith" (Box 11)
  - "Main Street: 1947" (Box 11)
  - "Main Street: September 1958" (Box 11)
  - "Man and Boy" (Box 11)
  - "A Man on One Leg" (Box 11)
  - "The Man with the Ring in His Nose" (Box 11)
  - "The Man with the Ring in His Nose" Ver. 2 (Box 11)
  - "The Many Make a Number" (Box 11)
  - "Math and Miss Webster" (Box 11)
  - "A Member of the Family" (Box 11)
  - "Memory is a High Gray Wall" (Box 11)
  - "The Miami Maid Special" (Box 11)
  - "The Midnight Mixer" (Box 11)
  - "Mr. Kirby" (Box 12)
  - "The Muse" (Box 12)
  - "Nearly Everybody is Doing Better than Kleinstuber" (Box 12)
  - "Never a Way to Die" (Box 12)
  - "Never a Way to Live" (Box 12)
  - "Never a Way to Live" Ver. 2 (Box 12)
  - "Never a Way to Live" Ver. 3 (Box 12)
  - 'The New Dark" (Box 12)
  - "A New Death" (Box 12)
  - "No Smoking" (Box 12)
  - "No Wonder that I Wander" - draft with corrections (Box 12)
  - "Nun Hath No Nation" (Box 12)
  - "Old-Fashioned Girl" - draft with corrections (Box 12)
  - "The Old Jockey" (Box 12)
  - "Old Roots Never Die" (Box 12)
  - "The One Hundred Orphans" (Box 12)
  - "The Only Thing to Do" (Box 12)
  - "The Other Life" - draft with corrections (Box 12)
  - "The Other Life" - handwritten draft (Box 12)
  - "Our Great War" (Box 12)
  - "Parade" (Box 12)
  - "Patient Doing Well" (Box 12)
  - "A Private Invasion" (Box 12)
  - "Pop Wins with Horseshoes" (Box 12)
  - "Pop Wins with Horseshoes" Ver. 2 (Box 12)
  - "The Problem of Reality" (Box 12)
  - "The Problem of Reality" Ver. 2 (Box 12)
  - "The Quiet of the House" (Box 12)
  - "Really Good Friends" (Box 12)
  - "Return and Farewell" (Box 12)
  - "The Return of Seraphitus" (Box 12)
  - "The Ring" (Box 12)
  - "RIOT" (Box 12)
  - "The Sea Change" (Box 12)
  - "The Seduction of Rosebud" (Box 12)
  - "The Seduction of Rosebud" Ver. 2 (Box 12)
  - "The Seed and the Flowers" (Box 12)
  - "The Shock Treatment" (Box 12)
  - "Shoes" - Various drafts Part 1 (Box 12)
  - "Shoes" - Various drafts Part 2 (Box 12)
  - "The Shortest Journey" (Box 12)
  - "Silly Girl" (Box 12)
  - "Silly Girl" Ver. 2 (Box 12)
  - "Silly Girl" Ver. 3 (Box 12)
  - "Silly Girl" Ver. 4 (Box 12)
  - "Silly Girl" - draft with corrections (Box 12)
  - "Silly Girl" - miscellaneous 1 (Box 12)
  - "Silly Girl" - miscellaneous 2 (Box 12)
  - "The Soldier" (Box 12)
  - "Something About the Moon" (Box 12)
  - "Something for the Children" (Box 12)
  - "Sometimes I Wonder" (Box 12)
  - "Special Delivery" (Box 12)
  - "Special Delivery" Ver. 2 (Box 12)
  - "The Spoiled Boy" (Box 12)
  - "The Suicide" - various drafts (Box 12)
  - "Summer Session" (Box 12)
  - "Sunday Faithful" (Box 12)
  - "The Telegrams" (Box 12)
  - "Then the Music Starts" (Box 12)
  - "There's a Man Coming 'Round Taking Names" (Box 12)
  - "There"s Nothing to Be Done About It" (Box 12)
  - "There's Nothing You Can do About It" (Box 12)
  - "Things Ended, Things Begun" (Box 12)
  - "This is For Louis" (Box 12)
  - "The Three Goodbyes" (Box 12)
  - "The Three of Them" (Box 12)
  - "To the Beginning Again" (Box 13)
  - "To the Beginning Again" Ver. 2 (Box 13)
  - "The Tomboy" (Box 13)
  - "Too Long to Tell" (Box 13)
  - "Twenty Questions" (Box 13)
  - "Two Old Men" (Box 13)
  - "The Two-Thousand Years War" (Box 13)
  - "The Unwise Serpent" (Box 13)
  - "The Way It Had to Be" (Box 13)
  - "What Are We Doing Here?" (Box 13)
  - "What It Means" (Box 13)
  - "When the Lilacs Bloomed" (Box 13)
  - "When the Music Starts" (Box 13)
  - "White Tremendous Daybreak" (Box 13)
  - "Widows" (Box 13)
  - "Widows" - draft with corrections (Box 13)
  - "A Winter in Spain" (Box 13)
  - "The Wise Old Bird" (Box 13)
  - "Within a Moment Invisible" (Box 13)
  - "Without Children" (Box 13)
  - "The Wooing" (Box 13)
  - "The Wrong Man" (Box 13)
  - "You Take What You Can Get" (Box 13)
  - Undergrad Work
    - "An American Screen: I. Christening" (Box 13)
    - "The Cloud" (Box 13)
    - "Country Wife" (Box 13)
    - "Hands" (Box 13)
    - "Pound Party" (Box 13)
    - Unknown (Box 13)
  - Unknown 1 (Box 13)
  - Unknown 2 (Box 13)
  - Unknown 3 (Box 13)
  - Unknown 4 (Box 13)
  - Unknown 5 (Box 13)
  - Unknown 6 (Box 13)
  - Unknown 7 (Box 13)
  - Unknown 8 (Box 13)
  - Unknown 9 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 1 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 2 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 3 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 4 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 5 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 6 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 7 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 8 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 9 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 10 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 11 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 12 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 13 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 14 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Part 15 (Box 13)
- V. OTHER WRITINGS
  - Autobiography
    - Part 1 (Box 13)
    - Part 2 (Box 13)
    - Part 3 (Box 13)
    - Part 4 (Box 13)
    - Part 5 (Box 14)
    - Part 6 (Box 14)
    - Part 7 (Box 14)
    - Part 8 (Box 14)
    - Part 9 (Box 14)
    - Part 10 (Box 14)
    - Part 11 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 2 Part 1 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 2 Part 2 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 2 Part 3 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 2 Part 4 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 2 Part 5 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 2 Part 6 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 3 Ch. 1-3 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 3 Ch. 4-6 (Box 14)
    - Ver. 3 Ch. 7-10 (Box 14)
    - Misc 1 (Box 14)
    - Misc 2 (Box 14)
    - Misc 3 (Box 14)
  - Living Language textbook
    - Book 12, Ch. 1 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 2 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 3 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 4 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 5 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 6 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 7 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 8 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 9 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 10 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 11 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 12 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 13 (Box 14)
    - Book 12, Ch. 14 (Box 14)